{
    "easy": [
        {
            "question": "When was WoW released in Europe?",
            "correctAnswer": "2005",
            "answer1": "2004",
            "answer2": "2003",
            "answer3": "2006"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the source of Deathwing's madness?",
            "correctAnswer": "Old Gods corruption",
            "answer1": "Influence of ancient artifact",
            "answer2": "Burning Legion schemes",
            "answer3": "Death of his dragonflight"
        },
        {
            "question": "Forsaken can speak in-game in...",
            "correctAnswer": "Their own Forsaken-only language and orcish",
            "answer1": "Orcish and human",
            "answer2": "Orcish, human and their own language",
            "answer3": "Human and their own language"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of Burning Legion leader?",
            "correctAnswer": "Sargeras",
            "answer1": "Archimonde",
            "answer2": "Kil'Jaeden",
            "answer3": "Mannoroth"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mankrik from Barrens lost his...",
            "correctAnswer": "Wife",
            "answer1": "Dog",
            "answer2": "Son",
            "answer3": "Daughter"
        },
        {
            "question": "The organization known as Scarlet Crusade pursuits...",
            "correctAnswer": "All Undead",
            "answer1": "Scourge",
            "answer2": "The Forsaken",
            "answer3": "Deamons"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is Sargeras?",
            "correctAnswer": "Titan",
            "answer1": "Powerful Deamon Lord",
            "answer2": "Fallen Naaru",
            "answer3": "Old God"
        },
        {
            "question": "Naaru are beings of..",
            "correctAnswer": "Light",
            "answer1": "Order",
            "answer2": "Justice",
            "answer3": "Magic"
        },
        {
            "question": "How did Draenei come to Azeroth?",
            "correctAnswer": "By a space ship",
            "answer1": "By a magical portal",
            "answer2": "teleported by Naaru",
            "answer3": "They were always on Azeroth"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which dragonflight doesnt exist in Warcraft Universe?",
            "correctAnswer": "Yellow Dragonflight",
            "answer1": "Red Dragonflight",
            "answer2": "Bronze Dragonflight",
            "answer3": "Black Dragonflight"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many different kinds of deamons can warlock summon?",
            "correctAnswer": "7",
            "answer1": "6",
            "answer2": "5",
            "answer3": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Death Knight's starting zone you have to kill... ",
            "correctAnswer": "A prisoner from your own race",
            "answer1": "Prisoners from each of your faction's races",
            "answer2": "A summoned magical being mirroring your moves",
            "answer3": "Random prisoner from opposite faction"
        },
        {
            "question": "When did mages get Blink spell?",
            "correctAnswer": "They had it from beginning",
            "answer1": "In The Burning Crusade",
            "answer2": "At some point in Classic WoW",
            "answer3": "in Wrath of the Lich King"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which statements regarding Warrior's Rage resource is not true?",
            "correctAnswer": "It decays in combat",
            "answer1": "Warrior gains it by getting damage",
            "answer2": "Warrior gains it by dealing damage",
            "answer3": "It decays out of combat"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is Warsong Gulch located?",
            "correctAnswer": "In Ashenvale",
            "answer1": "In the Barrens",
            "answer2": "In Feralas",
            "answer3": "In Azshara"
        },
        {
            "question": "Dire Maul was originally inhabited by...",
            "correctAnswer": "Elves",
            "answer1": "Ancient Ogres",
            "answer2": "Trolls",
            "answer3": "Humans"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Dark Portal is located in...",
            "correctAnswer": "Blasted Lands",
            "answer1": "Badlands",
            "answer2": "Swamps of Sorrow",
            "answer3": "Tanaris"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where can you encounter Tuskarr?",
            "correctAnswer": "In Northrend",
            "answer1": "In Winterspring",
            "answer2": "In northern Pandaria",
            "answer3": "In Shadowmoon Valley"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Cho'gall race?",
            "correctAnswer": "Ogre",
            "answer1": "Orc",
            "answer2": "Deamon",
            "answer3": "Human"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the color of Mage class?",
            "correctAnswer": "Light blue",
            "answer1": "Dark blue",
            "answer2": "Purple",
            "answer3": "White"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a form Druid cannot shapeshift into?",
            "correctAnswer": "Wolf",
            "answer1": "Stag",
            "answer2": "Seal",
            "answer3": "Lion"
        },
        {
            "question": "How is Draenor related to the Azeroth?",
            "correctAnswer": "It is another planet",
            "answer1": "It is another plane of existence",
            "answer2": "It is a parto of Elemental Plane",
            "answer3": "It is another continent"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is Temple of Ahn'Qiraj located?",
            "correctAnswer": "In Silithus",
            "answer1": "In Badlands",
            "answer2": "In Swamps of Sorrow",
            "answer3": "In Nagrand"
        },
        {
            "question": "Warlock's class color is...",
            "correctAnswer": "Purple",
            "answer1": "Pink",
            "answer2": "Brown",
            "answer3": "Red"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where can you meet Archmage Khadgar?",
            "correctAnswer": "In Shattrath",
            "answer1": "In Naxxramas",
            "answer2": "In Dalaran",
            "answer3": "In Stormwind"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is Ulduar located?",
            "correctAnswer": "In Northrend",
            "answer1": "In Tanaris",
            "answer2": "In Draenor",
            "answer3": "in Badlands"
        },
        {
            "question": "Kirin'Tor is organization of...",
            "correctAnswer": "Mages",
            "answer1": "Priests",
            "answer2": "Light-worshippers",
            "answer3": "Scribes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where are the Echo Isles located?",
            "correctAnswer": "South of Durotar",
            "answer1": "South of Dustwallow March",
            "answer2": "East of Azshara",
            "answer3": "Near Darkshore"
        },
        {
            "question": "Can mages use swords?",
            "correctAnswer": "Yes",
            "answer1": "Yes, but only spellpower ones",
            "answer2": "No",
            "answer3": "No, but they used to"
        },
        {
            "question": "Cenarius is a demigod worshipped by...",
            "correctAnswer": "Night Elves",
            "answer1": "Blood Elfes",
            "answer2": "Humans",
            "answer3": "Orcs"
        }
    ],
    "medium": [
        {
            "question": "Death Knight tanking spec used to be...",
            "correctAnswer": "All three specializations",
            "answer1": "Blood and Frost",
            "answer2": "Blood and Unholy",
            "answer3": "Always only Blood"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the size of original Zul'Aman instance?",
            "correctAnswer": "10 man raid",
            "answer1": "20 man raid",
            "answer2": "5 man dungeon",
            "answer3": "40 man raid"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Grim Batol",
            "correctAnswer": "Old dwarven stronghold",
            "answer1": "Ancient human city",
            "answer2": "First orcish stronghold in Azeroth",
            "answer3": "Ogre Stronghold"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is Anub'Arak?",
            "correctAnswer": "Former king of Nerubians",
            "answer1": "One of Quiraj emperors",
            "answer2": "A Deamon Lord",
            "answer3": "Powerful Lich"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was Kel'thuzad before he became the Lich Lord?",
            "correctAnswer": "Mage",
            "answer1": "Warrior",
            "answer2": "Priest",
            "answer3": "Paladin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the last boss of Trial of the Crusader?",
            "correctAnswer": "Anub'Arak",
            "answer1": "The Lich King",
            "answer2": "Lord Jaraxxus",
            "answer3": "Twin Val'kyr"
        },
        {
            "question": "Loken was...",
            "correctAnswer": "Titan Watcher",
            "answer1": "Titan",
            "answer2": "Frost Giant",
            "answer3": "Dwarf"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Great Sundering was the event when...",
            "correctAnswer": "Well of Eternity was destroyed",
            "answer1": "Deathwing destroyed part of Azeroth",
            "answer2": "Draenor was shattered into pieces",
            "answer3": "Draenei homeworld was destroyed"
        },
        {
            "question": "Vol'jin is the chieftain of...",
            "correctAnswer": "Darkspear Tribe",
            "answer1": "Zandalari Tribe",
            "answer2": "Raventusk Tribe",
            "answer3": "All troll tribes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Pandaren...",
            "correctAnswer": "Were only represented as a single hero in Warcraft RTS game",
            "answer1": "Used to be a regular unit in Warcraft RTS game",
            "answer2": "Were made up for Mists of Pandaria based on Blizzard artists drawings",
            "answer3": "Were made up as April Fools joke"
        },
        {
            "question": "Shattrath City factions, Aldor and Scryers",
            "correctAnswer": "Aldor are only Draenei, Scryers only Blood Elves",
            "answer1": "Aldor are only Blood Elves, Scryers only Draenei",
            "answer2": "Both factions have Draenei and Blood Elves",
            "answer3": "Both factions have members of all kinds of races"
        },
        {
            "question": "Time of the Argent Crusade is now!' is a quote from",
            "correctAnswer": "Tirion Fordring",
            "answer1": "Alexandros Mograine",
            "answer2": "Abbendis",
            "answer3": "Every Argent Crusade NPC"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is now the Lich King?",
            "correctAnswer": "Bolvar Fordragon",
            "answer1": "Arthas Menethil",
            "answer2": "Dranosh Saurfang",
            "answer3": "Tirion Fordring"
        },
        {
            "question": "Naga leader name is...",
            "correctAnswer": "Azshara",
            "answer1": "Vashj",
            "answer2": "Nazjatar",
            "answer3": "Neptulon"
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of trolls do not exist in Warcraft?",
            "correctAnswer": "Fire Trolls",
            "answer1": "Frost Trolls",
            "answer2": "Dark Trolls",
            "answer3": "Forest Trolls"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who created the talisman known as 'Deamon Soul'?",
            "correctAnswer": "Deathwing",
            "answer1": "Malygos",
            "answer2": "Lich King",
            "answer3": "Medivh"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which classes originally have quests for epic mounts?",
            "correctAnswer": "Paladin and Warlock",
            "answer1": "Paladin and Shaman",
            "answer2": "Shaman and Warlock",
            "answer3": "Only Warlock"
        },
        {
            "question": "WoW had the most subscribers during...",
            "correctAnswer": "Wrath of The Lich King",
            "answer1": "the Burning Crusade",
            "answer2": "Cataclysm",
            "answer3": "Classic"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the original Draenei home?",
            "correctAnswer": "Argus",
            "answer1": "Dreanor",
            "answer2": "Outland",
            "answer3": "It is a nameless another dimension"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the last boss in Blackwing Lair?",
            "correctAnswer": "Nefarian",
            "answer1": "Onyxia",
            "answer2": "Ragnaros",
            "answer3": "Vaelastrasz"
        },
        {
            "question": "Lok'Tar Ogar' means...",
            "correctAnswer": "Victory or Death",
            "answer1": "For the Horde",
            "answer2": "Arm Yourselves",
            "answer3": "To Victory"
        },
        {
            "question": "You can fight Darkmaster Grandling in...",
            "correctAnswer": "Scholomance",
            "answer1": "Stratholme (present)",
            "answer2": "Stratholme (past, through Caverns of Time)",
            "answer3": "Naxxramas"
        },
        {
            "question": "Can paladin's 'bubble' be removed?",
            "correctAnswer": "Yes, by some classes",
            "answer1": "Yes, by every class",
            "answer2": "Yes, but only by one class",
            "answer3": "No"
        },
        {
            "question": "Are there Ogre women in Warcraft universe?",
            "correctAnswer": "Yes, but not in WoW",
            "answer1": "Yes, and there are some in WoW",
            "answer2": "Yes, but they look the same as males",
            "answer3": "No, there are not"
        },
        {
            "question": "Rogues...",
            "correctAnswer": "Can use any one-handed weapon",
            "answer1": "Can use only daggers and swords",
            "answer2": "Can use only daggers and fist weapons",
            "answer3": "Can use only daggers"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Ravenholdt?",
            "correctAnswer": "Guild of thieves and assassins",
            "answer1": "Secret rogue-only inn located in Stormwind",
            "answer2": "Name of the highest peak in Alterac Mountains",
            "answer3": "Secret rogue-only tavern located in Orgrimmar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Garrosh Hellscream can be encountered in Outland in...",
            "correctAnswer": "Nagrand",
            "answer1": "Hellfire Peninsula",
            "answer2": "Terokkar Forest",
            "answer3": "Shadowmoon Valley"
        },
        {
            "question": "Malfurion and Illidan are...",
            "correctAnswer": "Brothers",
            "answer1": "Cousins",
            "answer2": "Unrelated powerful Night Elves",
            "answer3": "Unrelated, sworn enemies who used to be friends"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is Al'Akir?",
            "correctAnswer": "Lieutenant of the Old Gods",
            "answer1": "Lesser Air Elemental",
            "answer2": "Minion of Ragnaros",
            "answer3": "The leader of Ramkahen"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Deepholm?",
            "correctAnswer": "One of Elemental Planes",
            "answer1": "Place below ocean",
            "answer2": "Place deep below earth",
            "answer3": "Another planet"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which race is not native to Draenor?",
            "correctAnswer": "Draenei",
            "answer1": "Ogres",
            "answer2": "Orcs",
            "answer3": "Arakkoa"
        },
        {
            "question": "Lady Sylvanas was originally...",
            "correctAnswer": "A High Elf",
            "answer1": "A Night Elf",
            "answer2": "A Human",
            "answer3": "A Blood Elf"
        },
        {
            "question": "Azuregos belongs to the...",
            "correctAnswer": "Blue Dragonflight",
            "answer1": "Green Dragonflight",
            "answer2": "Red Dragonflight",
            "answer3": "Bronze Dragonflight"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was Jewelcrafting added to the game?",
            "correctAnswer": "In The Burning Crusade",
            "answer1": "At some point in Classic WoW",
            "answer2": "In Wrath of the Lich King",
            "answer3": "in Cataclysm"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Emerald Dream?",
            "correctAnswer": "A spirit world",
            "answer1": "An elemental plane",
            "answer2": "Another planet",
            "answer3": "Mirrored Azeroth that can be entered  while dreaming"
        },
        {
            "question": "Can paladin use staves?",
            "correctAnswer": "No",
            "answer1": "Yes",
            "answer2": "Yes, but only those without spellpower",
            "answer3": "No, but they used to"
        }
    ],
    "hard": [
        {
            "question": "In classic WoW the current king of Stormwind...",
            "correctAnswer": "Appeared as a NPC",
            "answer1": "Appeared as a child NPC",
            "answer2": "Was only mentioned in quests",
            "answer3": "Never appeared"
        },
        {
            "question": " 'Despair, so delicious' and 'Fear... so exhilarating' is a quote from...",
            "correctAnswer": "Captain Falric",
            "answer1": "Captain Marwyn",
            "answer2": "Arthas Menethil",
            "answer3": "Lady Sylvanas"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Old Gods were originally trapped under Azeroth surface?",
            "correctAnswer": "5",
            "answer1": "6",
            "answer2": "3",
            "answer3": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Naga originally used to be...",
            "correctAnswer": "Night Elves",
            "answer1": "They were always Naga",
            "answer2": "Blood Elves",
            "answer3": "Humans"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the race of first Lich King?",
            "correctAnswer": "Orc",
            "answer1": "Human",
            "answer2": "Forsaken",
            "answer3": "Deamon"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the mother of Medivh?",
            "correctAnswer": "Aegwynn",
            "answer1": "Garona",
            "answer2": "Azshara",
            "answer3": "No one knows"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was Medvih's title?",
            "correctAnswer": "The Last Guardian",
            "answer1": "The Keeper of Secrets",
            "answer2": "Destroyer of the Worlds",
            "answer3": "The Forsaken"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the source of Malygos' madness?",
            "correctAnswer": "Death of his dragonflight",
            "answer1": "Old Gods corruption",
            "answer2": "Twisted magic",
            "answer3": "Time travels"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first wielder of the Ashbringer sword?",
            "correctAnswer": "Alexandros Mograine",
            "answer1": "Darion Mograine",
            "answer2": "Arthas Menethil",
            "answer3": "Tirion Fordring"
        },
        {
            "question": "The name of Orcish tribe 'Mag'har' means...",
            "correctAnswer": "Uncorrupted",
            "answer1": "Unbreakable",
            "answer2": "Red-skinned",
            "answer3": "Unyielding"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why is there so few Blue Dragonflight?",
            "correctAnswer": "They were killed by Deathwing",
            "answer1": "Overuse of magic killed many of them",
            "answer2": "They lost a war to Red Dragonflight",
            "answer3": "They were always so few"
        },
        {
            "question": "What lies beneath Oshu'Gun in Nagrand?",
            "correctAnswer": "An imprisoned Naaru",
            "answer1": "An imprisoned Deamon Lord",
            "answer2": "Naaru artifacts",
            "answer3": "Ancient Naaru power crystal"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who killed king Llane Wrynn?",
            "correctAnswer": "Garona Halforcen",
            "answer1": "Gul'Dan",
            "answer2": "Orgrim Doomhammer",
            "answer3": "Burning Legion"
        },
        {
            "question": "Ner'zhul was originally...",
            "correctAnswer": "Shaman",
            "answer1": "Warlock",
            "answer2": "Warrior",
            "answer3": "Hunter"
        },
        {
            "question": "Garrosh Hellscream was empowered by the power of",
            "correctAnswer": "Y'Shaarj",
            "answer1": "N'Zoth",
            "answer2": "C'Thun",
            "answer3": "Yogg-Saron"
        },
        {
            "question": "The ancient hydra Aku'mai can be encountered in...",
            "correctAnswer": "Blackfathom Deeps",
            "answer1": "Wailing Caverns",
            "answer2": "Razorfen Kraul",
            "answer3": "Razorfen Downs"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Skywall?",
            "correctAnswer": "Air elementals stronghold",
            "answer1": "Great wall in the Pandaria",
            "answer2": "The wall that used to separate Worgen kingdom",
            "answer3": "Wall of Stormwind"
        },
        {
            "question": "What or who destroyed Auchindioun?",
            "correctAnswer": "Evil magic",
            "answer1": "Orc under Burning Legion influence",
            "answer2": "One powerful Burning Ledion lord",
            "answer3": "Its unknown"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the fate of Drakuru?",
            "correctAnswer": "He was slain by the Lich King",
            "answer1": "He was slain by the players",
            "answer2": "He still lives as a Scourge lord",
            "answer3": "He was turned into lesser Scourge minion"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many times was Sylvanas model changed?",
            "correctAnswer": "Twice",
            "answer1": "Once",
            "answer2": "Triple",
            "answer3": "It was just improved several times"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the origin of Worgen?",
            "correctAnswer": "Druids worshipping wolf god",
            "answer1": "Ancient alchemy",
            "answer2": "Curse from Twisting Nether",
            "answer3": "Mage Arugal's magic"
        },
        {
            "question": "What or who are Loa?",
            "correctAnswer": "Spirits worshipped by Trolls",
            "answer1": "Troll lucky talismans",
            "answer2": "Troll weapons",
            "answer3": "Eldest Trolls"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is Terokk?",
            "correctAnswer": "Arakkoa's god",
            "answer1": "Arakoa's leader",
            "answer2": "Ancient Arakkoa's hero",
            "answer3": "The lost capital of Arakkoa"
        },
        {
            "question": "Xavius was orginally...",
            "correctAnswer": "A Night Elf",
            "answer1": "A lesser deamon",
            "answer2": "A powerful deamon",
            "answer3": "A human"
        },
        {
            "question": "War of the Ancient was fought between",
            "correctAnswer": "Elves and Burning Legion",
            "answer1": "Human and Orcs",
            "answer2": "Factions of Elves",
            "answer3": "Dragons and mortal races"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is Krasus?",
            "correctAnswer": "Consort of the Alexstrasza",
            "answer1": "Leader of the Kirin Tor",
            "answer2": "Powerful Elf",
            "answer3": "Deathwing's minion"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who or What was Arathor?",
            "correctAnswer": "First human empire",
            "answer1": "One of human Capitals",
            "answer2": "Great human hero",
            "answer3": "First human king"
        },
        {
            "question": "Amani was the empire of...",
            "correctAnswer": "Forest Trolls",
            "answer1": "Dark Trolls",
            "answer2": "Frost Trolls",
            "answer3": "Neither of them"
        },
        {
            "question": "Devourer of Souls is a boss from...",
            "correctAnswer": "Forge of Souls",
            "answer1": "Dark Temple",
            "answer2": "Halls of Stone",
            "answer3": "Naxxramas"
        },
        {
            "question": "What happended to King Magni Bronzebeard?",
            "correctAnswer": "He was turned into statue",
            "answer1": "Nothing, he rules as the King of Ironforge",
            "answer2": "He was slain in battle",
            "answer3": "He went missing"
        },
        {
            "question": "Khaz Modan means...",
            "correctAnswer": "Mountain of Khaz",
            "answer1": "Land of Dwarfes",
            "answer2": "Kingdom in the Mountains",
            "answer3": "The Highest Peak"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the War of the Spider?",
            "correctAnswer": "War between Scourge and Nerubians",
            "answer1": "War between Trolls and Quiraj",
            "answer2": "War between Nerubians and humans",
            "answer3": "War between Quiraj and Nerubians"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was Thrall's father?",
            "correctAnswer": "Durotan",
            "answer1": "Grom",
            "answer2": "Kargath",
            "answer3": "Orgrim"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Taurahe?",
            "correctAnswer": "Language of Tauren",
            "answer1": "Kingdom of Tauren",
            "answer2": "Race similar to Tauren",
            "answer3": "Name of Tauren mythology"
        }
    ]
}